19 Oak Tree Drive Landenberg, PA 19350 bdaghir@gatech.edu 484-667-7453 (mobile) 610-255-0727 (home)

### **SUMMARY**

I have proven to be a forward-thinking leader who can undertake long-term projects and successfully execute them with a team of diverse individuals. My research experience and ability to effectively self-teach new information has drastically impacted my ability to explore and solve new and complex problem spaces. I expect my work experience to also be a learning experience.

## PROJECTS, RESEARCH, AND SKILLS

- **Rotorcraft Computational Simulator:** I am currently building a rotorcraft comp. sim. that will eventually run machine learning algorithms to better land rotorcraft on moving aircraft carriers experiencing stochastic winds and waves.
- **Grand Challenges:** My team has submitted a proposal to conduct research in the Materials Science department during the 2017 Fall semester. I am currently exploring and designing the insulation properties of special paints for low-income households.
- **Eagle Scout:** I renovated a high school baseball field to improve drainage and decrease rain damage.
- Other Skills: Proficient in MatLab, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Autodesk AutoCAD®, Adobe Products, Microsoft Office, XYZware®, custom 3d-modeling and additive manufacturing, soldering.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Georgia Institute of Technology School of Aerospace Engineering**

2016 - Current

GPA: 4.000 / 4.000

Completed Credit Hours: 47 / 132

Honors:

- Earned Faculty Honors for the first year
- Member of the National Society of Collegiate Scholars

# Saint Mark's High School Four Year College Preparatory High School 2012 – 2016

GPA: 4.000 / 4.768 (unweighted / weighted)

Honors:

- Ronald R. Russo Jr. Memorial Award: The top Senior in Academic Excellence
- St. Francis de Sales award: The highest honor awarded by the Archdiocese of Wilmington.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### **Facilities and Maintenance**

Avon Grove Charter School
West Grove, PA

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

The responsibilities of this job included logistical planning, facility repair and renovation, moving furniture, and painting.

Work Hours: 40+ hours per week

Reference: Jason Knox – jknox@agcharter.org (Facilities Manager)

## **Usher/Operator**

Wilmington Blue Rocks Minor League Baseball
Wilmington, DE

Jun 2016 – Aug 2017

I worked as an usher and operator in the children's amusement section of the stadium for every home game.

Work Hours: 12 – 21 hours per week

Reference: Andrew Layman - layman@bluerocks.com (Assistant General Manager)